jonathan@felchlin.net (253) 394-2507

User Experience Developer

Professional Profile

7 years enterprise software development experience (with 14 years in varying capacities).

Advanced front-end developer, competent through the full stack.

Strong understanding of advanced Javascript concepts such as objects, closures, scope, variable hoisting, OOP, promises, and functional programming.

A passion for clean, efficient, and reliable code with an emphasis on unit-testing and adherence to standards.

Areas of Expertise

•	Javascri	nt
•	javastii	μι

- Responsive CSS/LESS
- PHP and Java

Python

• SQL

YUI, JQuery

- {{mustache}}
- Git

Agile process

Work Experience

2012 – 2015 2vr 6mo

2012 – 2015 UX Developer / Zillow, Seattle, WA

Worked with a small team of developers, using Agile methods, to build client-facing web tools and services. At the enterprise level, I helped drive the adoption of tools such as LESS, Mustache templating, an enterprise style-guide, and modern coding standards.

Related expertise: *Javascript, responsive LESS/CSS, Python, Java, Git, YUI, TurboGears, Node*

Key projects: schools rewrite, home values rewrite, sitewide responsive navigation, Zillow.com homepage redesign

1yr 4mo

2011 – 2012 | UX Developer / Razor Planet, Renton, WA

Developed templates, plugins, and core functionality for an inhouse content management system built on CakePHP and JQuery. Worked in small teams to design and develop custom applications such as a job board and survey engine.

Related expertise: Javascript, JQuery, CSS, PHP, SVN, CakePHP

Key projects: *templates, client-side image tool, online personality* test

2008 - 2011 *3yr.* 1mo.

Programmer Analyst / Costco Wholesale, Issaguah, WA

Developed in-house accounting applications, services, and processes. Made heavy use of the Rational Unified Process and IBM Rational tools. Designed relational database models and wrote stored procedures.

Related expertise: RPG IV, Java, SQL, DB2, UML, MS Visio, RUP

Key projects: *custom accounts receivable system, coupon* processing

experience 1996 - 2008

Other work | Web Developer-Analyst / IT Support, Northwest Church, Federal Way, WA (1 year)

> Manager of Internet Operations, Customized Tours, Seattle, WA (2 years)

Client Services/Technical Support, University of Washington, Seattle, WA (1 year)

Programmer/Internet Support, Icehouse Net Services, Spokane, WA (1 year)

Master Control Operator, KHQ Incorporated (Q6), Spokane, WA (1 year)

Satellite Communications Network Operator/Maintainer, US Army (4 years)

Education

2008	IBM System i Programmer Training, Costco Wholesale, Issaquah, WA
2002 - 2004	Computer Science and Math Focus, University of Washington, Seattle, WA
2000 - 2002	Associates of Science (Engineering / Math emphasis), Spokane Falls Community College, Spokane, WA
1996	Satellite Operator Maintainer Course, 35 Wks, US Army Signal School, Ft. Gordon, GA